Inventory of O.41 - Collection of Lists and Documentation Regarding Those Who Perished and Those Who Were Persecuted During the Holocaust Period O.41
O.41 - Collection of Lists and Documentation Regarding Those Who Perished and Those Who Were Persecuted During the Holocaust Period
- Lists of Jewish students rejected by Humboldt University in Berlin, and a list of Quakers who helped Jews, date empty; 9 List of persecuted persons List of students Letter xerox; O.41/948
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Fuchs-Kittowski Klaus, Dr. Prof
  Lists of Jewish students rejected by Humboldt University in Berlin, and a list of Quakers who helped Jews
  - Lists of Jewish students rejected by Humboldt University in Berlin, date empty; 5 List of students List of persecuted persons; O.41/948.1
    Jewish students; Universities and colleges; Berlin,Berlin,Berlin,Germany
    Lists of Jewish students rejected by Humboldt University in Berlin
    The list/s contain approximately 167 names
  - List of Quakers from Germany who helped Jews, date empty; 1 List of persecuted persons; O.41/948.2
    Quakers; Berlin,Berlin,Berlin,Germany; <>,<>,<>,Germany
    List of Quakers from Germany who helped Jews
- Personal documentation on Chil Yechiel Alpert, survivor, born in Kielce, Poland, date empty; 7 Personal documents List of camp inmates Record of survivors Official documentation Certification xerox; O.41/411
  Kielce,Kielce,Kielce,Poland; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland; Mauthausen,Camp,Austria; Gusen,Camp,Austria; Linz,Upper Austria,<>,Austria
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by אלפרט יחיאל
  Personal documentation on Chil Yechiel Alpert, survivor, born in Kielce, Poland The file also contains a list of survivors, Chil Yechial Alpert's record card from the Mauthausen subcamp Gusen, and documents given to him by the Hospital in Linz following his liberation from the camp in 1945.
- Confirmation of the transport of Auschwitz prisoners, Mueller Bela and Mueller Adolf, Holocaust survivors, to Gross-Rosen and Dachau camps, date empty; 1 Record of survivors Certification xerox; O.41/415
  Auschwitz,Camp,Poland; Dachau,Camp,Germany; Gross Rosen,Camp,Germany
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by דוב (בלה) מילר
  Confirmation of the transport of Auschwitz prisoners, Mueller Bela and Mueller Adolf, Holocaust survivors, to Gross-Rosen and Dachau camps
- Documentation regarding the mass murder in Kremnicka, 11/1944-03/1945, and a report regarding the exhumation of the corpses from the mass graves in Kremnicka and Nemecka, date empty; 56 List of murdered persons Death certificate Letter Reports xerox; O.41/419
  Exhumation; Kremnicka,Zvolen,Slovakia,Czechoslovakia; Nemecka,Zvolen,Slovakia,Czechoslovakia
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by ע"י שגרירות ישראל בוינה
  Documentation regarding the mass murder in Kremnicka, 11/1944-03/1945, and a report regarding the exhumation of the corpses from the mass graves in Kremnicka and Nemecka Included in the file: - Report prepared by Daniela Baranova regarding the exhumation of the corpses from the mass graves in Kremnicka and Nemecka, 1946.
  - List of people murdered in Kremnicka, 11/1944-01/1945, with a report regarding the opening of the mass graves in Kremnicka, 1946, date empty; 30 List of murdered persons; O.41/419.1
    Banska Bystrica,Zvolen,Slovakia,Czechoslovakia; Kremnicka,Zvolen,Slovakia,Czechoslovakia
    List of people murdered in Kremnicka, 11/1944-01/1945, with a report regarding the opening of the mass graves in Kremnicka, 1946
  - List of inmates from Banska Bystrica prison who were murdered in Kremnicka, 11/1944-01/1945, Zoznam zavrazdenych vaznov v banskobystrickom koncentraku, ktori boli zastreleni v Kremnicke; 03/03/1947-03/03/1947; 10 List of murdered persons; O.41/419.2
    List of inmates from Banska Bystrica prison who were murdered in Kremnicka, 11/1944-01/1945
- Documentation regarding the Jews from Cherven who were murdered, and regarding the commemoration of the people who were murdered, dated, 1967-1969, 1967-1969; 323 List of murdered persons Official documentation Diagram Photograph Handwritten, original Typewritten original; O.41/958
  Commemoration; Monuments; Cherven,Cherven,Minsk,Belorussia (USSR)
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by צודיק ריטוב
  Documentation regarding the Jews from Cherven who were murdered, and regarding the commemoration of the people who were murdered, dated, 1967-1969 - List of Jews from Cherven who were murdered, 02/02/1942; - Lists of the donors for the conservation of the mass graves and the establishment of a monument to commemorate the victims; - Technical diagrams; - Correspondence between official organizations regarding the establishment of a monument to commemorate the people who were murdered; - Article from the "Uperad" newspaper, 05/06/1968, with a description of the dedication ceremony for the monument, 1968.
  - List of Jews from Cherven who were murdered, 02/02/1942, prepared based on testimonies of relatives, Евреи, убитые немцами в г. Червене Минской области 2 февраля 1942 года; 1968-1968; 18 List of murdered persons; O.41/958.1
    Cherven,Cherven,Minsk,Belorussia (USSR)
    List of Jews from Cherven who were murdered, 02/02/1942, prepared based on testimonies of relatives
    The list/s contain approximately 928 names
- List of Jews from Mezokovesd and the Mezokovesd vicinity who perished during the Holocaust, and list of survivors who contributed toward the establishment of the local monument, 1946-1946; 77 List of murdered persons List of survivors Yizkor book xerox Handwritten; O.41/421
  Commemoration; Bequeathing the Holocaust; Mezokovesd,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Borsodivanka,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Negyes,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Ostoros,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Noszvaj,Heves,<>,Hungary; Novaj,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Szentistvan,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Borsodszemere,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Szihalom,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Szomolya,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Bogacs,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Bukkzserc,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Cserepfalu,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Andornaktalya,Borsod,<>,Hungary
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by אמזל גאורג
  List of Jews from Mezokovesd and the Mezokovesd vicinity who perished during the Holocaust, and list of survivors who contributed toward the establishment of the local monument The memorial book was edited by Mihaly Eisler and Jakab Land.
  The list/s contain approximately 885 names
- Personal documents of Egon Glas, from Bruenn, who perished in Auschwitz, 08/12/1941, 08/12/1941-01/01/1948; 3 Personal documents Death certificate Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/371
  Bruenn,Brno Hlavni Mesto,Moravia-Silesia,Czechoslovakia; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by גלס מיכה
  Personal documents of Egon Glas, from Bruenn, who perished in Auschwitz, 08/12/1941 Included in the file are: Certificates of excellence issued posthumously by the Government of Czechoslovakia to Egon Glas and Frantiska Glasova, 1946-1948.
- List of Jewish women inmates from Hungary and Сarpathian Ruthenia in Salzwedel camp who were forced laborers in a weapons factory, 1944-1944; 34 List of camp inmates Letter List of inmates xerox; O.41/375
  Labor camps; Women prisoners; Women Workers; Women; Salzwedel,Camp; <>,<>,<>,Hungary; <>,<>,Carpathian Ruthenia,Czechoslovakia
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by חפר פנינה
  List of Jewish women inmates from Hungary and Сarpathian Ruthenia in Salzwedel camp who were forced laborers in a weapons factory The file includes a letter from the submitter of this material, with information concerning the creation of the list.
  The list/s contain approximately 1079 names
- Documentation regarding members of the Mueller family from Breslau who perished in the Holocaust, 1942-1957, 25/06/1942-18/02/1957; 10 Certification Letter List of murdered Jews xerox Original Handwritten; O.41/378
  Letters; Breslau,Breslau,Silesia (Lower),Germany
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by מילר לוטר, ברלין, גרמניה
  Documentation regarding members of the Mueller family from Breslau who perished in the Holocaust, 1942-1957 Also in the file: - Letter from Luzie (Mueller) Scharff in Breslau to Lothar Mueller, submitter of the material, 31/06/1942.
  - List of the Mueller family members from Breslau, who perished during the Holocaust, 18/02/1957-18/02/1957; 1 List of murdered Jews; O.41/378.1
    Breslau,Breslau,Silesia (Lower),Germany
    List of the Mueller family members from Breslau, who perished during the Holocaust
- Certificates issued by the Jewish National Fund in 1966 certifying trees were planted after Razevsky and Shapshelewitz family members, who perished in the Holocaust, 15/09/1966-14/10/1966; 4 Personal documents Record of murdered persons Original; O.41/383
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by שפר אפרים ומרים
  Certificates issued by the Jewish National Fund in 1966 certifying trees were planted after Razevsky and Shapshelewitz family members, who perished in the Holocaust
- Documentation regarding Frampol during the Holocaust, and commemoration of the victims after the war, date empty; 36 List of murdered persons Diagram Survey Print Handwritten; O.41/387
  Commemoration; Jewish hostages; Ghettos; Frampol,Yarmolintsy,Kamenets Podolsk,Ukraine (USSR)
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by פוקס נינל
  Documentation regarding Frampol during the Holocaust, and commemoration of the victims after the war - List of Jews who perished in Frampol; - Survey report by Alexander Liebman regarding the fate of the Jews of Frampol (pp. 345-366); - Map of the ghetto [apparently, the Frampol Ghetto], prepared by Alexander by Liebman (pp. 379-380).
  - List of Jews from Frampol who perished, 1941-1944, Фамилии погибших семей; date empty; 9 List of murdered persons; O.41/387.1
    Frampol,Yarmolintsy,Kamenets Podolsk,Ukraine (USSR)
    List of Jews from Frampol who perished, 1941-1944
- Documentation regarding Soviet citizens who perished during World War II, including those who perished in Zembin and Borisov, 1994-1994; 11 List of murdered persons List of soldiers Survey Newspaper clippings Print; O.41/394
  Zembin,Borisov,Minsk,Belorussia (USSR); Borisov,Borisov City,Minsk,Belorussia (USSR); Zembin,Ghetto; Borisov,Ghetto; Moskva,Moskva City,Moskva,Russia (USSR)
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by שגרירות במינסק
  Documentation regarding Soviet citizens who perished during World War II, including those who perished in Zembin and Borisov - List of Jews from Borisov who perished as Red Army soldiers; - List of Jews from Zembin who perished, 18/08/1941; - Four early articles published in Borisov that were dedicated to the Holocaust victims; - Article from the Moscow newspaper "Izvestia" regarding the establishment of a computerized data bank containing the names and a list of all the Soviet citizens who perished during World War II; article published, 07 May 1994.
  - List of Jewish soldiers from Borisov, who died in battle, 1941-1945, Светлой памяти евреев-борисовчан, павших в борьбе с фашизмом; 1994-1994; 2 List of murdered persons List of soldiers; O.41/394.1
    Borisov,Borisov City,Minsk,Belorussia (USSR)
    List of Jewish soldiers from Borisov, who died in battle, 1941-1945
    The list/s contain approximately 292 names
  - List of Jews from the Zembin Ghetto, who were murdered, 18/08/1941, Поминальное слово о жертвах Зембинского гетто; 1994-1994; 2 List of murdered persons; O.41/394.2
    Zembin,Ghetto
    List of Jews from the Zembin Ghetto, who were murdered, 18/08/1941
- Confirmation that Marcel Levy of Saloniki, a Holocaust survivor, was an Golleschau-Auschwitz III inmate during 1943-44, date empty; 6 Personal documents Record of survivors List of camp inmates Certification Typewritten copy Typewritten original; O.41/404
  Saloniki,Thessaloniki,Macedonia,Greece; Saloniki,Ghetto; Golleschau,Camp; Auschwitz III - Monowitz,Camp,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by לוי מרסל
  Confirmation that Marcel Levy of Saloniki, a Holocaust survivor, was an Golleschau-Auschwitz III inmate during 1943-44
- List of Jews from Chernigov who perished, 1941-1943, Светлой памяти евреев-черниговцев, павших жертвами фашизма в оккупации в 1941-1943 годах; date empty; 6 List of murdered persons xerox; O.41/408
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by קגן פליקס
  List of Jews from Chernigov who perished, 1941-1943
- List of those who perished from the Taurage region, Lithuania, 29/06/1945-29/06/1945; 24 Reports List of murdered persons xerox; O.41/412
  Taurage,Taurage,<>,Lithuania
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by לוי עזריאל
  The list/s contain approximately 1329 names
- Registration forms of Marianne (Van Abbe) Blampied, Hyam Goldman and Esther Pauline Lloyd, from Jersey, the United Kingdom, and a letter written by Joseph Miere in Jersey to the director of Yad Vashem in Jerusalem, 1994, with a list of Jews who were registered by the authorities in Jersey and Guernsey, 1940, 01/10/1940-04/11/1994; 9 Personal documents Identity card List of Jewish residents xerox; O.41/416
  Guernsey,Channel Islands,<>,United Kingdom; Jersey,Channel Islands,<>,United Kingdom
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by מיר ג'וזף
  Registration forms of Marianne (Van Abbe) Blampied, Hyam Goldman and Esther Pauline Lloyd, from Jersey, the United Kingdom, and a letter written by Joseph Miere in Jersey to the director of Yad Vashem in Jerusalem, 1994, with a list of Jews who were registered by the authorities in Jersey and Guernsey, 1940 Included in the file: - Letter sent by Joseph Miere in Jersey to the director of Yad Vashem in Jerusalem, 04 November 1994, with a list of Jews who were registered by the authorities in Jersey and Guernsey, 1940, and information regarding the experiences of the Jews in the Channel Islands.
  - Partial list of Jewish residents of Guernsey and Jersey, 10/1940, Jews people registred in Guersey and Jersey. Channel Islands. Oktober 1940; 04/11/1994-04/11/1994; 1 List of Jewish residents; O.41/416.1
    Partial list of Jewish residents of Guernsey and Jersey, 10/1940
- List of Jews from Norway whose money and property were confiscated by the Nazis, date empty; 4 List of persecuted persons Letter xerox; O.41/950
  Confiscation of Jewish property; <>,<>,<>,Norway
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Mjaland Arne
  List of Jews from Norway whose money and property were confiscated by the Nazis
- Documentation regarding the deportation of the Jews of Halberstadt, 04-11/1942, date empty; 11 List of deportees Photograph Newspaper clippings Letter Original Typewritten; O.41/379
  Deportation of German Jews; Halberstadt,Magdeburg,Saxony Province,Germany; Warszawa,Warszawa,Warszawa,Poland; Theresienstadt,Litomerice,Bohemia,Czechoslovakia
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by שוואב שלום
  Documentation regarding the deportation of the Jews of Halberstadt, 04-11/1942 - Lists of Jews from Halberstadt who were deported to Warsaw and Theresienstadt, 04-11/1942; - Two letters by Willy Calm, chairman of the Jewish community of Halberstadt, written to Hermann Schwab in London, including information regarding the deportation of the Jews of Halberstadt; - German newspaper clippings, 1953; - Photograph of the deportation of the Jews of Halberstadt.
  - List of Jews from Halberstadt deported to Warsaw and Theresienstadt, 04-11/1942, date empty; 3 List of deportees; O.41/379.1
    Deportation of German Jews; Halberstadt,Magdeburg,Saxony Province,Germany; Warszawa,Ghetto; Theresienstadt,Ghetto,Czechoslovakia
    List of Jews from Halberstadt deported to Warsaw and Theresienstadt, 04-11/1942
- Documentation regarding the Jews of Mozyr during the war, including lists of the Jews from Mozyr who perished, and other documentation, 1944-2004, 01/01/1944-01/01/2004; 91 List of murdered persons Research article List of ghetto inmates Letter Official documentation xerox; O.41/951
  Suicides; Commemoration; Antisemitism after the war; Mozyr,Mozyr City,Polesye,Belorussia (USSR)
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Goodman Yakov
  Documentation regarding the Jews of Mozyr during the war, including lists of the Jews from Mozyr who perished, and other documentation, 1944-2004 - Lists of Jews from Mozyr who perished; - Testimony of Olga Telesh regarding the suicide of 21 Jews in Mozyr, autumn 1941 (p. 317); - Research by Yakov Gutman regarding the Jews of Mozyr during the Holocaust (pp. 336-350); - Copies of photographs regarding the commemoration of the victims of the Holocaust; - Correspondence by the submitter of the material, Yakov Gutman, with official organizations in Mozyr, regarding the commemoration of the victims of the Holocaust (pp. 351-401).
  - List of Jews from Mozyr who committed suicide, Autumn 1941, Спис жыхароу г. Мазыра, парвергнууших сябе у гады акупацыі горада немцамиі самаспаленню у доме № 19 па вул. Пушкіна у 1941 г; 06/08/1996-06/08/1996; 2 List of murdered persons; O.41/951.1
    Suicides; Mozyr,Mozyr City,Polesye,Belorussia (USSR)
    List of Jews from Mozyr who committed suicide, Autumn 1941
  - List of Jews from Skrygalov, and its surrounding villages, who were deported to Mozyr, Список жидов Скригаловского сельсовета, подлежащих отправке в г. Мозырь; 1941-1942; 3 List of deportees; O.41/951.2
    Skrygalov,Mozyr,Polesye,Belorussia (USSR); Mozyr,Mozyr City,Polesye,Belorussia (USSR)
    List of Jews from Skrygalov and its surrounding villages who were deported to Mozyr
  - List of Jews from Kamenka, and its surrounding villages, who were deported to Mozyr, Список жидов Скригаловского сельсовета, подлежащих отправке в г. Мозырь; 1941-1942; 3 List of deportees; O.41/951.3
    Kamenka,Mozyr,Polesye,Belorussia (USSR)
    List of Jews from Kamenka and its surrounding villages who were deported to Mozyr
  - List of Judenrat members in Mozyr, 17/12/1941, Список еврейского совета мозырской еврейской общины на 17 декабря 1941 года; 1941-1941; 2 List of ghetto inmates List of Judenrat members; O.41/951.4
    Judenrat; Mozyr,Mozyr City,Polesye,Belorussia (USSR); Mozyr,Ghetto,Belorussia (USSR)
    List of Judenrat members in Mozyr, 17/12/1941
  - List of Jews in the Mozyr Ghetto, 17/12/1941, Список Мозырской еврейской общины на 17 декабря 1941 года; 1941-1941; 18 List of ghetto inmates; O.41/951.5
    Mozyr,Ghetto,Belorussia (USSR)
    List of Jews in the Mozyr Ghetto, 17/12/1941
- Announcement that the Rabinowicz family perished in Lanowce, Tarnopol district, Poland, 16/01/1941-25/07/1945; 6 Personal documents Letter Photograph Record of murdered persons Original; O.41/686
  Last letters; Commemoration; Lanowce,Krzemieniec,Wolyn,Poland; Tel Aviv,<>,<>,British Mandate For Palestine
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by רבינוביץ שרה
  Notification about the fate of the Rabinowicz family who perished in the Holocaust in the village of Lanowce, Tarnopol Region Announcement dated 25/7/1954 that the Rabinowicz family perished in Lanowce, Tarnopol district, during August 1942. The file also contains a picture of the memorial commemorating the Holocaust victims in the Lanowce village. Holocaust Survivor Page (which was transferred to the Hall of Names). The last postcard the submmiter received in Israel from her parents in the Tarnopol region dated 16/01/1941.
- Confirmation regarding the fate of the Adler family members from Vozokany, who were deported to Auschwitz, 06/1944, 05/08/1946-05/08/1946; The file was created by URADU VLADNEHO KOMISAR VO VOZOKANOCH; 1 Personal documents Certification Record of murdered persons Record of survivors xerox; O.41/704
  Vozokany,Nitra,Slovakia,Czechoslovakia; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by אדלר משה
  Confirmation regarding the fate of the Adler family members from Vozokany, who were deported to Auschwitz, 06/1944
- Birth certificates of the children of Hersz Pawlowski and Dwojra Pawlowski Slodkowicz, from Lodz, Odpis skrocony aktu urodzenia; 23/02/1949-30/10/1987; 12 Personal documents Record of persecuted persons xerox; O.41/694
  Lodz,Lodz,Lodz,Poland; <>,<>,<>,France
  Birth certificates of the children of Hersz Pawlowski and Dwojra Pawlowski Slodkowicz, from Lodz Included in the file: Correspondence regarding the search for the inheritors of Bina Pawlowski.
- Notification by the Red Army that Red Army soldier Meylakh Simons, from Mogilev, was Missing In Action in battle as of August 1943, and death certificate of Frida Simons, who died in Kirghizstan at the age of 15 due to heart disease, 22/12/1943, 05/09/1990-05/09/1990; 2 Personal documents Certification Death certificate Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/707
  Jewish soldiers in the Red Army; Mogilev,Mogilev City,Mogilev,Belorussia (USSR); <>,<>,<>,Kirghizstan (USSR); the Soviet armed forces,<>,<>,<>
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by ירמן ברוריה
  Notification by the Red Army that Red Army soldier Meylakh Simons, from Mogilev, was Missing In Action in battle as of August 1943, and death certificate of Frida Simons, who died in Kirghizstan at the age of 15 due to heart disease, 22/12/1943
- List of Jews from Trencin who were deported, 1942-1945, 31/03/2001-31/03/2001; 19 List of deportees List of murdered persons List of survivors Names of Jewish partisans xerox; O.41/660
  Deportation from Slovakia; Trencin,Trencin,Slovakia,Czechoslovakia
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by רינגולד דוד
  List of Jews from Trencin who were deported, 1942-1945
  - List of Jews deported from Trencin who perished, 1942-1945, Obcania z Trencina Deportovani a Zavrazdeni 1942-1945; 31/03/2001-31/03/2001; 12 List of deportees List of murdered persons Names of Jewish partisans; O.41/660.1
    List of Jews deported from Trencin who perished, 1942-1945
    The list/s contain approximately 1560 names
  - List of Jewish survivors from Trencin, 31/03/2001-31/03/2001; 7 List of survivors; O.41/660.2
    Trencin,Trencin,Slovakia,Czechoslovakia
    List of Jewish survivors from Trencin
- Document confirming the fate of Gerson Steinmanis and his family members from Riga, who perished during the Holocaust; document dated, 1957, 09/04/1957-20/04/1999; 2 Personal documents Letter Certification Page of Testimony Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/737
  The material was aquired by Yad Vashem from LATVIJAS VALSTS VESTURES ARHIVS - LATVIA, RIGA
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by יעוז תמרה
  Document confirming the fate of Gerson Steinmanis and his family members from Riga, who perished during the Holocaust; document dated, 1957
- Notification by the Red Army that Red Army soldier Meir Elkis, from Shargorod, died in battle in Poland, 17/08/1944, 17/09/1955-17/09/1955; 1 Certification Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/700
  Jewish soldiers in the Red Army; Shargorod,Shargorod,Vinnitsa,Ukraine (USSR); the Soviet armed forces,<>,<>,<>
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by ELKIS FIRA
  Notification by the Red Army that Red Army soldier Meir Elkis, from Shargorod, died in battle in Poland, 17/08/1944
- Confirmation from the Red Cross regarding the fate of Eliezer Eskenazi, born in Istanbul, Turkey, deported from Paris to the Drancy camp and transferred to Auschwitz, 19 July 1942, 09/12/1953-27/10/1958; 4 Official documentation xerox; O.41/670
  Istanbul,<>,<>,Turkey; Paris,Seine,<>,France; Drancy,Camp,France; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by אשכנזי אלברט
  Confirmation from the Red Cross regarding the fate of Eliezer Eskenazi, born in Istanbul, Turkey, deported from Paris to the Drancy camp and transferred to Auschwitz, 19 July 1942
- Statistical data regarding mass graves of Jews murdered in the Wolyn, Rowno and Khmelnitsky (Kamenets)-Podolski districts, date empty; 7 Statistical data xerox; O.41/658